♪ It seems today
that all you see ♪
♪ Is violence in movies
and sex on TV ♪
♪ But where are those
good old-fashioned values ♪
♪ On which we used to rely?
♪ Lucky there's a family guy
♪ Lucky there's a man
who positively can do ♪
♪ All the things that make us
♪ Laugh and cry
♪ He's... a...
Fam... ily... Guy! ♪
♪ Family Guy 12x14 ♪Fresh Heir
新鲜的继承人
翻译&注释: 螃蟹阿雪 校对：wloverp 压制: @familyguy贴吧字幕组
旅游频道出品
The Travel Channel presents,
与穿短裤的罗圈腿一起
"Backpacking Through Europe with a Bowlegged Man
背包游欧洲
in Short Shorts."
嗨 来 一起看看这些美丽的景色
Hello. Come, let's see some beautiful sites together.
嗨 大树 谢谢你遮阴纳凉
Hello, Tree.Thank you for shade.
嗨 山猫
Hello, Mountain Cat.
谢谢你控制当地老鼠数量
Thank you for controlling local rat population.
嗨 风车
Hello, Windmill.
谢谢你的奶酪和冷却蛋蛋
Thank you for the cheese ride and ball cooling.
下周带来 子弹头列车
Next week, bullet trains.
你好...!
Hello...!
嘿 爸 你忙吗?
Hey, Dad. Are you busy?
我想我们可以一起做点啥
I was thinking we could spend some time together.
好 你是电视机吗
Okay, are you a television set,
或者互联网?
or the Internet?
不是
No.
哦 那就不行 抱歉
Oh, then no.No, thank you.
确定?
Are you sure?
这周末休息三天
Cause there's a three-day weekend coming up
我想也许我们终于可以去钓鱼了
and I thought maybe you and I can finally go fishing
我们说过的
like we've been talking about.
嗷 抱歉 Chris 不行 我有个疯子训练
Aw, sorry, Chris, I can't.I got insanity practice.
纸风车!头里有纸风车!
Pinwheels! Pinwheels in my head!
声音!愤怒的鱼!
Voices! Angry fish!
他怎样了?不太好
How's he doing?Not good.
他还以为这是某种"训练"
He still thinks this is "practice" of some sort.
但你答应过一起钓鱼的
But you promised we'd go fishing.
Chris 我骗你的好让你闪远点
Aw, Chris, I was just lying to you so you'd go away.
不过 如果你离开这 我会给你10亿美元
But, if you leave me alone now,I'll give you a billion dollars.
成交!
You've got a deal!
Peter 与父亲多相处相处
Peter, you know,i-it might help Chris
对Chris有好处
to be able to spend some time with his father.
嗯 这对老皮特有什么好处
Well, what's in it for ol' Pete?
他是你儿子
He's your son.
你难道不想有个人交流吗
Don't you want someone to bond with.
不 我只会无声的交流.
No. I only form unspoken bonds.
用你的最强一击来击垮我
♪ Hit me with your best shot
PAT BENATAR 的 Hit me with your best shot
为什么不用你的最强一击来击垮我
♪ Why don't you hit me with your best shot? ♪
♪
用你的最强一击来击垮我
♪ Hit me with your best shot
开火...
♪ Fire away...
你接连着来...
♪ You come on with a "come on"... ♪
好-好
O-Okay.
再联系 再见
I'll talk to you later. Bye.
大家 是我妈妈打来的
You guys, that was my mom.
她说爸爸摔断腿了
She said that Daddy broke his leg.
咋整的?!
How?!
显显然 他在商场伤到的
A-Apparently, he got hurt at the mall.
Carter 停下来
Carter, please stop doing that.
我们得给你买新灯芯绒裤子
We need to get you some new corduroys.
不!别的男孩都不穿灯芯绒!
No! None of the other boys are wearing corduroys!
我要买粗布的!
I want dungarees!
你这么做会受伤的
You're going to get hurt doing that.
不 我不会!我是做这个的行家!
No I'm not! I'm the champ at doing this!
嗷!你这个乌鸦嘴!
Ow! You jinxed me!
嗷 该死!
Aw, damn it!
嘿 叫那个带着肥老黑
Hey, call that beeping cart
到处逛的嘀嘀响的车
that carries around the fat black people.
我猜Babs停下自己的工作了吧
Well, I guess Babs has her work cut out for her.
事实上 妈妈不能照顾他 她出城了
Actually, Mom can't take care of him, she's out of town
给静脉杂志做封面
doing a photo shoot for the cover of Veins Magazine.
那么 你要去照顾他了 妈妈?
So, are you gonna go take care of him, Mom?
我不能 我要去给头发做微小改变
I can't go. I've got to go get my hair very minutely changed
然后在接下来的14小时试着让大家注意到
and then spend the next 14 hours trying to get people to notice.
如何
Well...?
Lois 闪开 你挡住电视了
Lois, move.You're blocking the TV.
你觉得怎样?
What do you think?
我认为你挡住电视了
I think you're blocking the TV.
Peter 有没有话想对我说呢?
Peter, i-is there anything you want to say to me?
好吧 Amy上班时吻我了
All right.Amy at work kissed me.
我没闪开是事实
It is true that I did not step away,
但我没伸过去
but I did not lean in.
不过 作为我的辩护
However, in my defense,
她最近去变了发型
she had recently gotten her hair done differently.
我在想其实你可以去帮帮爸爸
I was actually thinking that maybe you could go help Daddy.
呃 不去 妈妈
Well, not me, Mom.
上次我去祖父那
Last time I was at Grandpa's,
我西洋跳棋赢了他 他打了我的一个奶
I beat him at checkers and he punched one of my hogans.
那 Chris怎么样?
Well, what about Chris?
等-等下 Chris哪了
Wai-Wait, where is Chris?
他在楼上屋里
He's upstairs in his room.
奇怪了 他吃饭从不缺席
That's odd.He never misses a meal.
我我最好去看看他
I-I better go check on him.
嗯 说的没错
Yeah, good idea.
我最好去避风棚看看我的无毛双胞胎
I better check on my hairless twin in the storm shed.
关上门 月光灼人!
Close the door,the moonlight burns!
快到圣诞了 快到圣诞了
It's almost Christmas.It's almost Christmas.
圣诞节?!
Christmas?!
是 保证乖乖的
Yes. Keep being good
那么蛋壳和咖啡末就归你了
and all the eggshells and coffee grounds will be yours.
我能见见家人吗?
Can I meet the family?
你越线了!禁止过圣诞!
You've overstepped!No Christmas!
嘿 Chris 你还好吗
Hey, Chris. Are you okay?
我勒个去 这闻起来像屁味
Holy crap, it smells like farts in here.
这些是我的屁
Those are my farts.
为什么爸爸不愿意和我一起?
Why doesn't Dad ever want to spend time with me?
Chris 过来
Chris, come here.
坐下
Sit down.
你知道我爱你 对吧 宝贝?
You know I love you,right, sweetie?
妈 不要在我的贴画前面说
Mom... not in front of my posters.
还有你爸爸也爱你
And your father loves you, too.
他只是在表达情感上有障碍
He just has trouble expressing his emotions.
我爱Mike和Molly.
I love Mike & Molly!
麦克和茉莉, CBS轻喜剧, 讲两个单身的胖子
我爱Mike 我也爱Molly
I love Mike and I also love Molly!
我不在乎别人知道这!
And I don't care who knows it!
Chris 你还有外公
You know, Chris,you've got a grandpa
现在正需要你的帮助
who could use your help right now.
我确信他会乐意和你一起的
I'm sure he'd enjoy spending time with you.
好...我试一下吧
Okay... I'll give it a shot.
你不是准备自杀吧 是不?
You're not gonna kill yourself, are you?
这是我作为母亲可怕的污点记录
That would be a severe black mark on my record as a mom.
我必须编个故事说你有严重精神病
Oh, I'd have to make up stories of a severe mental illness.
做得像是你活这么久已经是个奇迹那样
Make is seem a miracle you made it this long.
我能做得来
I could do that.
你的腿这样 真是糟透了 祖父
Sucks about your leg, Grandpa.
你最近怎么样
How you been doin'?
嗯 我告诉你 糟透了
Well, let me tell you,this is awful.
我-我太无聊了
I-I'm so bored.
我睡不着 我-我只能躺着
I can't sleep,I-I just have to lie here
等我的蠢腿康复
and wait for my stupid leg to heal.
哦 我很难过 祖父
Oh, I'm really sorry, Grandpa.
最糟糕的部分是 我不能OOXX
And the worst part about it,is I can't have sex.
上帝!我希望有种办法能让我自己来
God! I wish there was a way I could just do it myself.
就-就4分钟内搞定然后小憩
You know, just-just to be done and napping within four minutes.
我给你展示点东西
Let me show you something.
这...太...棒...了!
That... was... amazing!
而且Lynda Carter刚才其实不在这?
And Lynda Carter wasn't actually here?
Lynda Carter 美国演员 演过神奇女侠
不!那只是你的想象
No! That was just in your mind.
难以置信!
Incredible!
所以-所以你可以做这个
So-So you can do that like,
比如 一年一次还是什么?
wh-what, once a year or something?
不 基本上你什么时候
No. You can do it basically
没事都可以做
whenever you're not doing something else.
酷!
Cool!
嘿 下次我想试试用我自己的手
Hey, next time I want to try it with my hand.
嘿 外公 我们现在做什么?
Hey, Grandpa.What should we do now?
你想订个披萨吗?
You wanna order a pizza?
嗯 听起来不太有兴趣
Well, that doesn't sound very exciting.
但现在可以在网上跟踪订单
But now you can follow your order online!
在这 它到范布伦了!
There it is.It's on Van Buren!
哦 哦 他快到这了
Oh. Oh. He's almost here!
哇哦 他真的很快 嘿 我有个点子
Wow, he's really fast.Hey, I got an idea,
我们下两个不同的订单 让他们比赛
let's put in two different orders and have 'em race!
你认为会让系统崩溃么?
You think it'll crash the system?
只有一种方式知道答案
Only one way to find out.
这是你的披萨 16.51刀
Here's your pizza.That's $16.50.
我们和你玩了个游戏
We were playing a game with you.
你就是这个 你是个小丑
That's what you are.You're a clown.
你会付钱吗?
Are you gonna pay for the pizza?
是的 你的钱在这堆土豆泥里
Yes. Your money is in this pile of mashed potatoes.
吃出来 不准用手
Eat your way out. No hands.
太有趣了 Chris 我喜欢和你一起玩
This is fun, Chris.I like hanging out with you.
别向上看 这部分与你无关.
Don't look up.You're not a part of this.
♪
听起来真的很不错 祖父
It's sounding really good, Grandpa.
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
抱歉我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
听着 Jason 你有认真对待吗?
Look, Jason, are you taking this seriously?
因为Chris和我是认真的
Because Chris and I take this seriously.
如果你彩排不出现
You know, if you're not gonna show up to rehearsal,
我们会找到愿意来的人 好吗?
we'll find someone else who will, all right?
我们想找点付费演奏! 抱歉 天啊
We want to get some paying gigs!Sorry. Geez.
记住 这关乎对我们有重要意义的音乐创作!
Remember, this is about writing music that means something to us!
好 从头开始
Okay, from the top.
荷氏润喉糖
♪ Halls Mentho-lyptus
你能从鼻子感觉它
♪ You can feel it in your nose ♪
这使你知道它是咳嗽药
♪ That's how you know it's a medicated cough drop ♪
不止是糖果
♪ And not just a candy.
嘿 我们能演奏首我的歌吗?
Hey, can we play one of my songs?
不!没人想听你的无意义傻歌
No! No one wants to hear your stupid songs about nothing!
现在 演奏"我掉进澡盆 所以也许我们的确需要那个肥皂"
Now, let's play "I Fell in the Shower,So Maybe We Do Need That Bar."
5 6 7 8!
Five, six,seven, eight!
听着 Chris 我真的想谢谢你
Listen, Chris, I really want to thank you
过来照顾我帮我康复
for coming to take care of me and helping me get well again.
哦 不是大事 嗯 对于我是
Oh, it was no big deal.Well, it is to me,
我想为你花费的时间给你点钱
and I want to give you some money for all your time.
别 你你不需要这样做
Come on, y-you don't have to do that.
我喜欢有时间和外公一起玩 你懂?
I just like getting to spend time with my grandpa, you know?
我...等 等 啥?
I... Wait, wait, what?
你 你不收这些钱?
You're... you're not gonna take the money?
不 我不想要你的钱
No, I don't want your money.
我和你一起玩很开心
I had fun hanging out with you.
那好吧 这样
Well, all right, then.
嘿 外公 看这个
Hey, Grandpa,check it out.
当我把手肘折成这样
When I make my elbow like this,
看起来像女人私处
it looks like women's private parts!
哦 Chris!你就是有套让事物看起来
Oh, Chris! You just have a way of looking at things
新鲜有趣的方式
that's delightfully fresh!
我们不应该做这个的
We're not supposed to be doing this.
我打赌我们不应该做这个
I bet we're not supposed to be doing this.
爸爸!你完全好了!
Daddy!You're all better!
没错 小南瓜
That's right, pumpkin.
而且我有个重要的事要宣布
And I have an important announcement to make.
我决定修改遗嘱
I have decided to change my will,
把我的外孙Chris
and name my grandson Chris
立为Pewterschmidt财产的唯一继承人
the sole heir to the Pewterschmidt fortune.
你什么?什么?哦 天!
You what?What? Oh, my!
哦不!我的无毛双胞胎逃跑了!
Oh, no!My hairless twin got out!
你们好 家人们
Hello, family.
让我们想吃什么垃圾就吃什么
Let's eat all the garbage we want.
爸爸 你是认真的要把财产都留给Chris?
Daddy, you're seriously leaving your entire estate to Chris?
我-我是说 妈妈怎么办
I-I mean,what about Mom?
我保证她死在我前面 我保证
I promise she'll be dead before I am. I promise.
但 外公 我都不想要这钱
But, Grandpa, I don't even want the money.
看?这正是我认为你应得的原因!
See? This is exactly why you should get it!
太新鲜了!
So refreshing!
呃 我-我也不想要钱
Well, I-I don't want it, either.
很好 因为你不会得到它的
Good, 'cause you're not getting it.
快点 你在做什么
Come on, what are you doing?
听着 Carter 你把我从你遗嘱你去除
Listen, Carter, you take me out of your will,
我要把你从我的里去除
I'm taking you out of mine.
Peter 那不是你的遗嘱 那是你的出生证明
Peter, that wasn't your will,that was your birth certificate.
哦 不!
Oh, no!
没有光!
There's no light!
只有烈火!
There's only fire!
听着 Carter 我想你有权做你想做的
Look, Carter, I suppose you're entitled to do what you want,
但 你知道 我是说 如果是我
but, you know, I'm just saying, if it were me,
我会把钱都捐给慈善组织
I would give all the money to charity.
哦 是吗?哪个慈善组织?
Oh, yeah?Which charity?
嗯 有太多这种
Well, there are just so many
做伟大的工作的组织
that do such great work.
举一个例子
Name just one.
呃 嗯 你知道的...
Um... well,you know...
可怜的 绿
Poor... Green...
鲸 枪支
Whale... Guns...
书?
Books?
你真是个大骗子
You are such a fraud.
为什么没人来帮我们?!
Why won't anyone help us?!
搞毛?!我不敢相信你爸
What the hell?I can't believe your dad's
把他的钱都给Chris了!
giving all his cash to Chris!
是很奇怪 毕竟最终还是他的钱
I know it's strange,but in the end it's his money,
所以谁在乎呢?
so who really cares?
嗯 是 但...
Well, yeah, but...
但是什么?
But what?
Peter...你娶我是为了我的钱吗?
Peter... did you marry me for my money?
当然不是 Lois 但你都不能否认
Of course not, Lois,but even you can't deny
那真是好大一比外快
it was always gonna be a huge perk.
我-我用对了吗?外快?对 Peter
D-Did I use that right? Perk?Yes, Peter.
是 我想也是 但就是我说出来
Yeah, I thought so,but then it just sounded
听上去有点怪异
kind of weird when I said it.
还好啦 谢谢
It was fine.Thanks.
总之 我不打算失去那笔钱一分一厘
Anyway, I don't plan on losing out on any of that money.
如果你问我 我们得马上开始讨好Chris
So if you ask me, we got to start sucking up to Chris right away.
啥?你-你说什么?
What? Wh-What are you talking about?
我在说拍Chris马屁
I'm talking about brownnosing Chris
然后讨他欢心得赏钱
and getting on his good side perk.
不 不对 不是"赏钱"
No, that's wrong.No "perk."
好 我错了 但我已经在算计那笔钱了 Lois
Okay, my bad. But I've been counting on that money, Lois.
钱对我的大计划很重要
It's always been critical to my master plan.
什么大计划?
What master plan?
听着 我从没给你讲过 不过...
Look, I never told you this, but...
好多年了, 我一直计划45岁退休,
for years now, I've been planning on retiring at 45
然后可以研究八兹海默的治愈良方
so I can work on finding a cure for Ballzheimers disease.
其实是阿兹海默症 老年痴呆
Peter 这些是睾丸吗?
Peter, are those testicles?
你-你从哪搞到的?
Wh-where did you get those?
我不记得了!
I don't remember!
嘿 嘿 他在这!
Hey, hey, there he is!
哦 天 热狗和任天堂 对吧 Chris?
Oh, boy, hot dogs and Nintendo, huh, Chris?
爸 你做什么?发生什么了?
Dad, what are you doing?What's going on?
不错啊 Chris!
Good one, Chris!
不错啊!你为什么穿成这样?
Good one!Why are you dressed like that?
我不知道 我-我就是有点觉得
I don't know. I-I just kind of felt
这才是炫酷装备
like this is what cool people wear.
嘿嘿 Chris 我和你一起做那种秘密握手方式
Hey, hey, Chris, how about you and me do a secret handshake
有很多步骤要记的那种 行不?
that has way too many steps to remember, all right?
好 握手 敲 敲 击掌 勾小指
Okay. Shake, bump, bump,slap, pinky hook,
假装把头发捋回去 伸手 敲
pretend to slick your hair back, represent, bump,
一转身 高击掌 低击掌
one spin, slap high, slap low,
反转身 敲 展开 握手 挠肚子
reverse spin, bump, explode,shake, belly rub,
假哈欠 手枪 搭车 搭车
fake yawn, finger gun,hitchhiker, hitchhiker,
摆摆摆摆摆 摇 摇 摇 敲
shimmy shimmy sham sham,shake, shake, shake, bump,
什么怪味 然后再握手
something smells and shake again.
行 准备好了么
Okay, ready?
哦 我的上帝 晚上了
Oh, my God, it's nighttime.
现在回到导演剪辑版碟中谍5
We now return to the director's cut of Mission: Impossible 5,
垫高台没被剪辑掉版本
with the step stools not edited out.
你要和我走因为我显然高于6英尺
You're coming with me because I'm definitely over six feet,
主演汤姆克鲁斯 身高不足6英尺
而且你不够帅
and you're not handsome.
嘿 Chris 嘿 你记得你说的
Hey, Chris, hey,you remember that kid
学校里欺负你那小孩吗?
you said was bullying you at school?
嗯 这是他的头!
Well, here's his head!
这根本不是他!
That's not even him!
这是那个聋孩子!
That's the deaf kid!
哦 那是手语
Oh, that was sign language.
我以为他用蹩脚的空手道
I thought he was trying to defend himself
在防卫
with terrible karate.
Chris 我要和你共享古老的父子传统
Chris, I want to share with you a timeworn father/son tradition.
我要给你看个我年轻时的很受欢迎
I am gonna show you a film comedy
的喜剧电影
from my youth that won't hold up.
欢迎来到经典喜剧 "肉丸子"
Welcome to the classic comedy,Meatballs.
哦 听起来不错
Oh, that sounds great.
是关于意面工厂还是什么的?
Is it about a pasta factory or something?
不 这是笑话的一部分
No, that's part of the joke.
这男人是谁?
Who's the guy?
这不是个男人 是热辣小妞!
That's not a guy.That's the hot chick!
她的咪咪呢?
Where are her boobs?
飞机场+美女脸是那年代
Flat with a decent face was the best
我们能看到最好的了
we could hope for back then.
Miley Cyrus和塑料手指做爱
Miley Cyrus had sex with a foam finger
Miley Cyrus美国90后歌手
中部时间晚上6点
at, like, 6:00 p.m.Central Time.
这电影有个小船慢慢地沉了
This movie has a canoe that slowly sinks.
好吧 你猜怎样? 算了吧!
All right, you know what?Forget it!
我要带走我的录像机 我的录像机清洁用带
I'm just gonna take my VCR,my VCR head-cleaning tape,
我的录像机清洁喷雾 我的清洁布
my VCR head-cleaning spray,my head-cleaning rag,
我的倒带机 然后见鬼地从这离开
and my rewinder, and just get the hell out of here.
现在回到"看电影" 讲用iPhone
We now return to At the Movies
看电影的两个男人
With Two Guys Who Watch the Films On Their iPhones.
晚上好 首先 我们要看
Good evening.First off, we're going
Paul Greengrass的菲利普船长
to review Paul Greengrass' Captain Phillips.
根据真实事件改编的2013年电影 Tom Hanks主演
你觉得怎样 Bill
What did you think, Bill?
嗯 它开头很棒，
Well, it got off to a great start,
但是到了我玩"拼词游戏"的轮次
but when it was my turn to play Words With Friends,
真的很让我出戏
it really took me out of it.
真可惜 因为视觉上...
Well, that's a shame,because visually...
噢!
Ooh!
再次回来 他们将会评论美国骗局
When we come back, the guys will review American Hustle.
2013年电影 又被戏称为美国洗剪吹
嗯?
Hmm?
嘿 大家
Hey, you guys.
天 Peter 你看起来疲倦极了
Geez, Peter,you look exhausted.
呃 是 过去几周我一直在
Ugh, I am. I've been busting my ass
花大力气讨好Chris
for the last week trying to suck up to Chris.
讨好Chris?这是为毛啊?
To Chris?What the hell for?
呃 Carter 算是决定
Well, Carter kind of decided
把他的钱都留给Chris了
he's gonna leave all his money to Chris.
我已在试着让他喜欢我了
So, I've been trying to get on his good side.
我甚至还有天打扫了他的房间
I even cleaned his room for him the other day.
真希望我没做那个
Wish I hadn't done that.
Chris 我们的洗澡水准备好了
Chris, our bath is ready.
我...呃...
I... uh...
我不...我不知道该做什么
I don't... I don't know what to do now.
我 我没有必备的家长技能
I... I don't have the parenting skills necessary
来处理此事
to deal with this.
我说我们就当没这事
I say we never speak of this again.
我...我也许会搬家了
I... I might move.
你知道吗?我说 对Chris来说不错
You know what?I say, good for Chris
还有对他娶的姑娘是好消息
and whatever lucky girl he ends up marrying.
嗯 或者是幸运的男人 如果他成了基佬
Yeah, or lucky guy,if he ends up being gay.
幸运的男人?
Lucky guy?
等一下
Wait a minute.
你们给了我启发!
You guys just gave me an idea!
他在上面做什么?他是只猫!
What's he doing up there?He's a cat!
他不能吹大号!
He can't play no tuba!
不 等下!
No, wait!
事实上 你们给了我两个启发!
Actually, you guys gave me two ideas!
我睡着时的嘟囔揭示梦的内容
Mumbling while I sleep to indicate dream content.
Chris Chris 醒醒
Chris, Chris, wake up.
我有重要事要问你
I have something very important to ask you.
Chris 这是每一个男人都会看着他儿子
Chris, there comes a time when every man looks at his son
想到 "我想要更进一步"
and thinks, "I want to take this to the next level."
Chris Griffin...愿意嫁给我吗?
Chris Griffin...will you marry me?
啥?!娶自己儿子难道合法吗?
What?! Is it even legal for a man to marry his son?
在Vermont州合法
It is in Vermont.
只要是两个男人 在那儿什么事都行
As long as it's a man and a man, anything goes up there.
他们是一群自由堕落的人
They're a bunch of liberal degenerates.
我不知道 感觉很诡异
I don't know.It seems really weird.
我是说 男人不是应该娶女人吗?
I mean, aren't men supposed to marry women?
不不不 那只是整个人类史
No, no, no, that's just all of human history
除去最后5个月的规则
except for the last five months.
我们会像最佳兄弟
We'll just be like best pals.
此外 还有很多人
And besides, there's plenty of people
结婚后不OOXX
who are married and don't have sex.
比如威尔史密斯和那条斗牛犬
Like Will Smith and that pit bull.
美国黑人影星 黑衣人系列
是什么让你想娶我
Why do you even want to marry me?
是时候安顿下来并简化一些事
It's time to settle down and simplify things,
比如只有一个银行卡和账号
like maybe having one ATM card and one bank account.
比如 你的
Say, yours.
哦 我懂了
Oh. I get it.
那么 你怎么说?
So, what do you say?
婚后 你得常与我一起吧
When you're married, you get to spend all your time together,
做点抛接游戏和钓鱼之类的 对吧?
doing things like playing catch and going fishing, right?
呃 最好的婚姻是给对方空间
Well, the best marriages give each other space,
但 是的 Chris
but, yes, Chris.
那么 好 我嫁给你 爸!
Then, yes, I will marry you, Dad!
哦 真是好消息!
Oh, that's wonderful news!
你应该知道这戒指很特殊
You should know this ring is very special.
曾经属于你妈妈
It used to belong to your mother.
等下 那妈妈怎么办?
Wait. What about Mom?
恐怕那段关系已经结束了 Chris
I'm afraid that's over, Chris.
Lois 醒醒
Lois, wake up.
我需要你签份法律文件
I need you to sign this legal document.
啥?这这是啥?
Huh? Wha-What is this?
这是要求家长会那个辣妈
It's a petition to force that hot mom
穿正常点的请愿书
to wear something appropriate at PTA meetings.
哦 谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
马上要与我儿子结婚了
不 爸
No, Dad.
我再也不知道什么才是正常了
I don't know what normal is anymore.
欢迎来Vermont 死于滑雪的最佳地点
所以现在你知道我的情史了 Chris
So now you know my complete sexual history, Chris.
哇哦 我很惊讶你被戴假发的熊耍了
Wow. I'm surprised you got fooled by a bear in a wig.
不是假发 是一种发型
It wasn't a wig,it was a hair system.
好吧 随便你
Well, whatever.
我们为什么有这么多预约?
Why do we have all these appointments?
婚礼DJ  花匠
Wedding DJ, florist.
因为 Chris 准备完美婚礼要花时间计划
Because, Chris, it takes time to plan a perfect wedding.
你不想行动过快
You don't want to jump the gun.
比如你回短信太快
You know, like when you respond to a text too quickly.
约朋友来过夜 应该很有趣
太棒 我有空 我去!
我妻子会读她的10-12个小故事
厨房用具
那么 我们应该先去婚姻登记所吧?
So, should we get started with your bridal registry?
是 呃 我想精装厨房
Yeah, um, I'd like to furnish my kitchen
搞得像是世界上最好的厨师那样
as if I'm the greatest chef in the world,
虽然我从不做饭
even though I've never cooked before.
这就是我们做的!好 棒极了
That's what we do!Okay, great.
好 我们以9千刀
All right, we'll start with the nine grand
铜底炊具开始
in copper-bottom cookware.
我了个去!
Holy wack-a-zoly!
爸 干什么?
Dad!What?
不要问我"干什么" 你知道你做了什么
Don't "what" me.You know what you did.
嘿 我也许是你丈夫和爸爸 但我还是正常男人
Hey, I may be your husband and your dad, but I'm still a man.
我们在找婚后周日早餐的地点
Yeah, we're looking to plan our post-wedding Sunday breakfast.
你懂 在大家都厌烦我们后
You know,when everyone's sick of us.
当然
Of course.
棒极了 你有为还没过完周末
Excellent. Do you have a table for the couple
就要分手的情侣准备的桌子吗
that barely made it through the weekend without breaking up?
当然 我能把他们放在
Absolutely. Can I put them near the couple
那对酒后勾搭上然后相互只有尴尬谈话
that hooked up drunk and now have to make awkward small talk
等待去机场出租车的情侣边上吗?
until their cab to the airport arrives?
当然 也许他们可以挨着
Sure. And maybe they could go next
穿得相当不合体的
to the vastly-underdressed cousin
但认为全世界都围着他转的表亲?
who thinks the world revolves around him?
我有合适的桌位
I have just the spot.
会有一个精神脆弱
Will there be a physically-frail,
敏感的叔叔吗?
fall-down uncle?
是的 我们想让他走个
Indeed. And we'd like to have him walk
椅子腿迷宫
through a maze of chair legs.
还有什么吗?有
Anything else?Yes.
我们确实邀请了一对黑人夫妇
We did invite a black couple.
呃 虽然我们3个月前刚认识
Um, even though we only met them three months ago,
但我们想让他们被精心安排
but we would like them to be prominently featured
好让别的客人知道我们有多包容高尚
to let the other guests know how tolerant and wonderful we are.
想到你们的第一支舞就兴奋
I'm excited for your first dance.
现在我们开始加音乐
And now we're ready to add music.
你们是什么音乐?
What's your song?
我思虑良久
You know, I've given it a lot of thought,
然后我选了史上最浪漫的歌
and I went with the most romantic song ever,
John Philip Sousa的星条旗永不落
"Stars And Stripes Forever" by John Philip Sousa.
♪
前进!前进!前进!前进!
March! March!March! March!
能感受到士兵吗 Chris
Can you feel the soldiers, Chris?
很多已经过逝
So many have fallen.
这就是他们要战斗的原因
And this is why they were fighting.
一个男人娶他的儿子
For a man to marry his son
在一个树丛密布的州
in a state with enough trees around
没人知道这是怎么回事
that nobody can see what's going on.
猫葬礼的客人们能留下来
It was nice of the guests at the cat funeral
真是太好了
to stay for our wedding.
是 我打赌你特高兴
Yeah, and I bet you're especially happy
我们能在周四结婚
we're getting married on a Thursday.
学校 讨厌 对不?!
School, yuck, right?!
欢迎 朋友们 挚爱们
Welcome, friends, loved ones,
以及等待3点旅馆入住但现在
and people who are waiting for the 3:00 check-in time
无事可做的人
with nothing better to do.
就让我们把包放那
Just let us put our bags in there.
我要拿我的短裤然后离开
I'm literally gonna grab my shorts and leave.
我知道你们两个已经写好誓词了?
I understand the two of you have written your own vows?
Chris 表达我的爱意
Chris, to express my love,
我用像我这种蓝领和新英格兰人渣
I turn to the words of the only poet that blue collar,
只会用的诗人的诗:Robert Frost
New England scumbags like me know: Robert Frost.
Robert Frost美国20世纪最受欢迎的诗人之一
森林中叉开了两条路 我...
"Two roads diverged in a wood, and I...
节选自 The Road Not Taken未选择的路
我选了人迹更少的路
I took the one less traveled."
我不是学者 但如果那不是
Now, I ain't no scholar,but if that's not a metaphor
一流肛交的隐喻 我不知道还有什么是
for major-league butt stuff,I don't know what is.
谢谢你 Chris？
Thank you. Chris?
中止婚礼!
Stop the wedding!
Lois 你怎么发现的?
Lois! How did you find out about this?
Peter 有人报警说
Peter, several people have called the police
一男人和他儿子结婚
about a man marrying his son.
这不正常!
It's not normal!
Peter? Peter Griffin?
哦 上帝
Oh, God.
你的所有前任都
Is everyone from your past here
要走过这条红毯吗?!
to walk you down the aisle?!
Peter你不能这么做!
Peter, you cannot do this!
你不能娶自己的儿子!
You cannot marry your son!
我不在乎爸爸留给他多少钱
I don't care how much money Daddy's left him.
别听你妈说的 Chris
Don't listen to your mother, Chris.
就是因为她我们才有就寝时间!
It's 'cause of her we have bedtimes!
Chris 过来 我们回家
Chris, come on,we're going home!
他不能逼你做这个
He can't make you do this.
但 妈妈 我想要做这个
But, Mom,I want to do this.
啥?
What?
我知道他为了钱娶我 但我不在乎
I know he's marrying me for my money, but I don't care.
爸和我花了比之前更多时间
Dad and I spent more time together planning this wedding
在一起准备婚礼
than we ever have before.
如果结婚意味着
And if being married means
我能和爸相处更多时间 那就值了
I get to spend even more time with my dad, then it's worth it.
等下 你一直知道我只是想要你的钱?
Wait. You knew all along I just wanted you for your money?
是的 爸 我知道
Yeah, Dad, I did.
哇哦
Wow.
哦 天 我真是个混球
Oh, boy, I've been a real jerk.
我很抱歉 Chris
I'm sorry, Chris.
但你猜怎样?
But you know what?
我要补偿你 现在开始
I'm gonna make it up to you, starting right now.
Chris Griffin 你愿意做我的儿子吗?
Chris Griffin...will you be my son?
愿意 爸爸
Yes, Dad.
哦我的神 摄影师 完全 被我迷上了
OMG, the photographer is,like, obsessed with me.
好 我们都回家吧 大家
Well, let's all go home,you guys.
我们今天的刺激已经够多了
I think we've had enough excitement for one day.
是 我学到了
Yeah, and I guess I learned
为了骗儿子的财产
it's wrong to take your son to Vermont
来Vermont
under false pretenses
与他结婚是不对的
to try to marry him for his inheritance.
你... 你理应知道的
You... you should've known that.
呃 我们应该走了
Well, we should probably get going.
我想这次冒险结束了
I think this adventure is over.
有趣的是 我确实又再次遇见了Chris
Interestingly, however,I did run into Chris again.
是在曼哈顿上西区
It was on the Upper West Side of Manhattan.
他跟着另一个爸 我和另一个儿子一起
He was with another dad.I was with another son.
但回忆旧时光还是很美好的
But it was nice reminiscing about old times.
儿童观看提示
For you kids watching,
这是伍迪艾伦电影蓝本
this is a reference to a Woody Allen movie.
指电影Annie Hall 影片多为回忆和对白
他也娶了他的一个孩子
He also married one of his children.
伍迪艾伦 娶过他的养女 相差35岁 最后的音乐:蓝月亮  伍迪艾伦电影蓝茉莉配乐